<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<match numberofquestions= '10'>
<pair  ><question  >Place within animal cells where the chromosomes are found.</question><answer>Nucleus</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >Differences between individuals of the same species.</question><answer>Variation</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >Type of reproduction in which offspring are identical to the parent.</question><answer>Asexual</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >Describes a characteristic that is visible if the individual has one allele for it.</question><answer>Dominant</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >Thread-like structures within each cell, containing the genes.</question><answer>Chromosomes</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >Cell division to form sex cells.</question><answer>Meiosis</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >The alleles for this characteristic are different, eg Gg.</question><answer>Heterozygous</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >The advantage of sexual reproduction is that it allows for ___ within the species.</question><answer>Variation</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >An individual who is homozygous for a particular trait can be described as ___-breeding.</question><answer>Pure</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >In sexual reproduction the offspring will be ___ from the parents.</question><answer>Different</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >After meiosis the chromosome number will be ___.</question><answer>Halved</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >Normal cell division.</question><answer>Mitosis</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >The visible outcome for a particular  characteristic.</question><answer>Phenotype</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >The part of a chromosome that codes for a particular characteristic.</question><answer>Gene</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >One of the forms a gene can take.</question><answer>Allele</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >A fertilised egg.</question><answer>Zygote</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >General term used to describe the organs in men and women where gametes are made.</question><answer>Gonads</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >The word used to describe sex cells.</question><answer>Gametes</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >A change or mistake in the DNA is a ___.</question><answer>Mutation</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >Both alleles for a particular characteristic are the same.</question><answer>Homozygous</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >The small molecules that make up the 'rungs' of the DNA molecule are called ___.</question><answer>Bases</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >Process of joining two gametes to make one cell.</question><answer>Fertilisation</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >A Punnett square can be used to predict the ___ of offspring having a specific characteristic.</question><answer>Probability</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >A large number of genetically similar organisms living very close together.</question><answer>Monoculture</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >Part of the body producing male gametes in humans.</question><answer>Testes</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >Type of square used to predict the outcome of a particular mating.</question><answer>Punnett</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >A shy or hidden gene is called ______.</question><answer>Recessive</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >Two chromosomes which carry genes for the same characteristics are said to be a ___ pair.</question><answer>Homologous</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >When two homologous chromosomes swap a chunk of genetic material.</question><answer>Crossing over</answer></pair>
<pair  ><question  >A mutation that is ___ will soon become common in the population.</question><answer>beneficial</answer></pair>


</match>
